这是上海的四马路
This is the Foochow Road in Shanghai
一九二二年武勇著名的马永贞
In 1922 Ma Yung Chen was ambushed at Qing Lin tower
在这里青莲阁受暗算重伤
and was mortally injured
被数十人围攻身中数斧而死
He was surrounded by many people who axed him to death
二十多年过去了
It's been more than 20 years
上海四马路的外貌变了
and the Foochow Road has changed
但内在并没有变
but only on the outside;
一样龙蛇混杂
Inside it is filled with low-lives
山东好汉马永贞
Ma Yung Chen of Shangtung
更已成为传说中的人物
has become a legend
一出极其类似的悲剧
A similar tragedy is about to
却就要在这同一条马路上演出
re-enact in this place
当然主角的名字换了
The hero's name has changed naturally
现在这个人是这一带响当当的
Our protagonist is a famous person in this vicinity
仇连环
Qiu Lian Huan
仇老板
Master Qiu
余先生 ， 这酒对不对啊？
Mr. Yu, is this wine alright?
余先生 ， 这酒...
Mr. Yu, this wine…
滚开滚开
Get lost
怎么？牌还没看出来啊？
What? Haven't decided yet?
老K
King
顺子怎么样？
Would it be a straight?
小开最喜欢玩牌
Xiao Kai likes card games
可能真是顺子
It might be a straight
该你出钱了
Your turn to call
厉害
Marvellous
我出一块
One dollar
你还有多少？
How much do you still have?
不比你少
Not less than you
你想偷鸡？
You want to chicken out?
这是两万三 ， 不够胆就别看
Here's 23 grand, you may give up if you have no guts
是满贯
A full house
又输了 ， 他妈的这牌怎么玩啊
Damn, I've lost again
菊芳 ， 走
Ju Fang, let's go
小开 ， 不玩了 ， 今天你又没输多少
Xiao Kai, don't go, you haven't lost much today
我劝你们也别来了
I suggest you go too
今天牌有鬼
the cards are possessed by a ghost today
你讲话清楚一点
Hey, mind what you say
还不清楚啊
What I say is clear enough
小朋友 ， 输不起别到这种地方来
Kid, if you can't bear to lose, don't play
拿去给你女朋友买糖吃
It's for you to buy candy for your girlfriend
金四虎 ， 把他给扔出来
Jin Xi Fu, bring him over
大家都是场上的人 ， 不要
We're all here just for fun, stop
不必人扔 ， 我自己会过来
I'll come over myself
放开他 ， 他不是充好汉的材料
Let him go, he's not such a tough guy
菊芳
Ju Fang
这个女人是谁？
Who is this woman?
黄浦滩上鼎鼎大名的交际花沉菊芳
The famous socialite Shen Ju Fang of Shanghai
老兄都不认识啊
You don't know her?
你老兄也是
I must say
何必和小开这种人动手
why did you fight with Xiao Kai?
他老头子可不好惹啊
His father is not a nice guy
是呀
Right
我知道
I know
仇连环？仇连环是什么人？
Qiu Lian Huan? Who is he?
你怎么会跟这种人一起坐在桌上
How come you sit at the same table with his kind?
老大 ， 你现在不大管外面的事情
Boss, you've been away from the scene for a while
有些新出道的小朋友你是不知道的
and don't know about the new upstarts
这仇连环在四马路
This Qiu Lian Huan is quite well known
也算是有点名堂
around Foochow road
已经够找我的麻烦了 ？
Enough to cause me problems?
那当然不够
Of course not
在黄浦滩上谁敢找你余大哥的麻烦
Who in Shanghai dares do that?
拿我的名片找那个仇连环
Get my card and bring that
到这儿来见我
Qiu Lian Huan to see me
是
Yes
走...
Go…
要钱用到账房去拿
If you need money get it from the treasurer
老大 ， 小开长大了
Boss, Xiao Kai has grown up
您的事情应该交给他来管了
you should hand over your affairs to him
根宝 ， 我跟你是老弟兄了
Gen Bao, we're old friends
怎么也来吃我的豆腐
don't pull my leg
他不是这块材料
He isn't of such calibre
我们的事还得靠我们老弟兄来撑着
Our affairs still require our own efforts
日本人才走 ， 市面乱
The city still unsettled as the Japanese have just left
我们正好趁机混水摸鱼
we can use the opportunity
发点胜利财啊
to make a quick buck
在那儿 ， 球在那儿
Over there, the ball is over there
怎么样？
Well?
算了 ， 那女人是余小开包着的
Forget it, that woman is kept by Yu Xiao Kai
我连门口都没走进
I haven't even stepped into the front door
笑话 ， 你没说是我想见她
Nonsense, you didn't say I want to see her
说了
I did
她门口的说没听说过你的名字
The doorman said he's never heard of you
在那儿 ， 问他要
It's over there. Ask him
把球还给我们吧...
Give us back the ball…
你跟他们打了 ？
You fought with them?
不错 ， 我的名字不够响
Right, my name is not as
比余震亭、 曾根宝他们这些大亨
popular as tycoons like Yu Zhen Ting Zeng Gen Bao
差得太远
It's still a long way off
踢得这么远
He kicked it far away
所以林更生要把他们这些人踢开去
That's why we want to kick these people away
我们才能出头
So we would not be over-shadowed by them
你...
You…
怎么？你怕了
Well? Are you afraid?
怕倒不怕
It's not that
可是从来就没有人敢惹他们
it's just that no one has ever messed with them
总要有人惹他们的
Someone has to sooner or later
你先回去
You go back first
有人找我
If anyone asks say I am at
就说我在愚园路沉菊芳家里
the home of Shen Ju Fang at Yu Yuan Road
那女人门口有十几个人守着
That woman has over 10 people guarding her door
你一去...
If you went there…
就是因为那样我才要去
That's precisely why I want to go there
只怕一脚踢在大石头上
You will run into trouble I'm afraid
"Shen Residence"
喂 ， 你干什么？
Hey, what are you doing?
我想见见沉小姐
I want to see Miss Shen
你是什么东西啊？
Who are you?
不是东西 ， 是人 ， 仇连环
I am Qiu Lian Huan
去你妈的
Damn you
要我打进去？
You want me to charge in?
你打听清楚了没有 ， 这是什么地方
Do you know what this place is?
沉寓
Shen residence
余先生在这里
Mr. Yu is here
我看你还是省省吧
Save it
笑话 ， 门口上又不是挂着余公馆
What ajoke, it doesn't say 'Yu Residence' on the door
我是来找这里的主人
I am here to see the master of the house
好 ， 你进去
Alright, if you go in
叫你直着进去横着出来
I'm sure you'll come out deadl
沉小姐 ， 要见你一面真不容易
Miss Shen, it's so difficult to see you
出去
Get out
叫他们出去
Ask them to get out
叫你出去
You get out
你弄错了吧
You're mistaken
一点也没弄错
Not at all
像你这种小捣乱能见我两次
An upstart like you is lucky
已经算是很好运气了
to see me twice
好
Alright
"Yu Zhen Ting"
余老板请仇老板吃顿便饭
Master Yu likes to invite Master Qiu over for dinner
仇老板不在 ， 我们不敢作主
As Master Qiu is not here we cannot decide
余老板请客没有人敢不来
No one dares to decline an invitation from Master Yu
我把话带给你也是一样
I am bringing you the message, it's just the same
那倒难说
That's not true
仇老板就在沉菊芳沉小姐那儿
Master Qiu is with Miss Shen
那儿你一定很熟
you must know that place well
还是再辛苦你走一趟吧
please make the trip again
要是余小开也在那儿
If Yu Xiao Kai is there as well
三朝六面就更好说话
it'd be easy to clear things up
请回吧
Please go back
走
Let's go
一得罪了余震亭事情可就麻烦了
If we get on Yu Zhen Ting's nerve we'll be in trouble
我知道 ， 可是没办法
I know, but we have no choice
饭桶 ， 你们这些吃粮不做事的饭桶
You nincompoops
省省吧 ， 就算你自己在又怎么样
What difference does it make even if you were there?
好 ， 仇连环
Alright, Qiu Lian Huan
你下我面子 ， 我要给你好看
I will teach you a lesson for this
你在这里发狠劲有什么用 ？
What's the use of your anger here?
你当了面去说啊
Go and speak to him
准备车子 ， 我去见老头子
Prepare the car, I'm off to see my dad
是
Yes
我看仇连环这小子
I think this kid Qiu Lian Huan
真可能不买你的面子
will not give you face
不会吧 ， 他是什么东西
I don't think so, who does he think he is?
好 ， 真好
Real good
我们做人活回去了
This isn't like our old time
什么事啊？
What's the matter?
曾老板
Master Zeng
仇连环下午到小开养的
This afternoon Qiu Lian Huan went to the girl who
那个女人那里大闹了一场
was kept by Xiao Kai and caused trouble
还打伤了很多的人呢
He injured many people there
又让他走了
We let him escape again
老头子
Old man
老头子 ， 我们不能再在上海住了
We can't stay in Shanghai anymore
搬到蒙古去吧
let's move to Mongolia
你叫什么？
What are you shouting?
叫我们自己的弟兄去找仇连环
Ask our men to seek out Qiu Lian Huan
不管他在那儿 ， 在做什么
regardless of where he is and what he's doing
拖他来见我
bring him to me
是
Yes
我也回去叫弟兄一起找他
I'll go back and ask our men to find him
由他这样下去那还了得
We can't let him go on like this
不过阵势也别太大了
But let's not make a big deal
倒显得他是个人物
or we'll exaggerate his importance
我也去
I'll go too
找着那个小子我先叫他吃一顿辛苦
When I find him I'll teach him a lesson
金四虎 ， 跟我走
Jin Xi Fu, come with me
好
Yes
我也走了 ， 回去安排一下
I'll go too and make arrangements
你别紧张
Don't be nervous
我们是什么人
remember who we are
这种小捣乱见得多了
we are used to his kind
他们想冒上来
They want to charge in
结果还不是全都进了枉死城
but will end up all dead
老大 ， 我打听过仇连环这个人
Master, I've heard things about this Qiu Lian Huan
人人都说他有一股不怕死的劲儿
people say he is not afraid of death
我看他当然拿我们没有办法
but he can't do anything to us
不过小开在外面树大招风
But Xiao Kai is attracting too much attention outside
你是说
You mean…
我不过是猜一猜
I was just guessing
叫小开小心一点
Ask Xiao Kai to be more careful
我走了
I'm leaving
曾老板...
Master Zeng
大家都过来
Come here, everyone
告诉你们有生意了
Business is here
你再到八仙桥去走一趟
Go to Bai Sin Bridge again
去叫点兄弟来
ask a few men to come here
是
Yes
走
Let's go
大家出点力
Put in your efforts, everyone
今天晚上就要仇连环好看
We'll teach Qiu Lian Huan a good lesson tonight
仇老板
Master Qiu
谢谢
Thanks
谢谢...
Thanks…
你...
You…
你搭架子 ， 我一定要把你弄到手
Trying to put on airs? I must get you
你已经把我弄到手了
You've already got me
不是你
I didn't mean you
别当我们不会还手
Don't think we wouldn't hit back
还手？就是要你还手
That's exactly what I want you to do
金四虎 ， 把他给扔出来
Jin Xi Fu, bring him over
仇连环在什么地方 ， 说
Where is Qiu Lian Huan? Speak
揍他
Beat him
妈的
Damn you
你不说也不要紧
It doesn't matter if you don't speak
我们在这儿等 ， 等到他回来
we'll wait here till he returns
放开他
Let him go
仇连环回来了
Qiu Lian Huan is back
仇老板
Master Qiu
你家里昨天来了很多人还没有走
Many people came to your home but haven't left
不要 ， 不...不要
No, don't
仇大哥 ， 你回来了
Brother Qiu, you're back
更生 ， 你放心
Geng Sheng, don't worry
他们怎么样对付你
Whatever they did to you
我照样对他们
we'll do the same to them
怎么样？把我这里打成这样
You messed up my place
话都没有一句
You should say something
我赔...
I'll pay…
打伤了我的人呢？
What about my men who have been injured?
医 ， 我医 ， 我去找最好的医生来医
I'll get them the best doctor
仇老板 ， 你面子也赚足了
Master Qiu, you have been given enough face
还不把小开放了
let Xiao Kai go
笑话 ， 你们打上门来
Nonsense, you charged in this place
还说我赚足了面子
and still say I've been given face?
随便你要怎么样 ， 你只管说好了
Just tell us what you want
跟你这种人说有什么用
What's the use of talking to you
我要带你去见你老头子
I'll take you to your dad
好 ， 你先放开我
Alright, let me go first
就这样去
We'll go this way
老板...他来得太快了
Boss…he came too fast
一下就冲到小开的面前
and got right to Xiao Kai
我...
l…
别说了
Enough
开大客厅准备迎接客人
Get the sitting room ready to welcome the guest
是
Yes
你们全出去
Go out all of you
是
Yes
他来了
He's here
带了多少人？
How many men has he brought?
没有 ， 就是他跟小开
None, just him and Xiao Kai
仇老板 ， 谢谢你送人回来
Master Qiu, thanks for bringing him
你一个人来 ， 佩服佩服
I admire your courage to come alone
黄浦滩上出了你这样一个人物
Someone like you has appeared in Shanghai
我们竟没有见过面
it's ajoke
这真是天大的笑话
we could have missed you
好说 ， 小开年纪轻
Xiao Kai is still young
又靠着余老板的牌头
and is backed by Master Yu
我要是出手重了 ， 余老板别怪
if I used too much force, please pardon me
什么话 ， 正应该有人教训教训他
No, someone should teach him a lesson
不要...
Don't…
你们还站着干什么？
What are you standing there for?
滚进去
Get in
等等 ， 你养的那个女人
Wait, the woman you harbour
本来就不是正经的东西
is not a proper person
仇老板喜欢
If Master Qiu likes her
你以后就别去见她
then you stop seeing her
不成
No way
你苦头还没有吃够啊？进去
Have you not had enough? Get inside
请坐啊
Please sit
我年纪虽然大了
I am old now
可是年轻的时候一样天不怕地不怕
but I too feared nothing when I was young
请坐啊
Please sit
这件事就这样算了
Let this matter rest
多谢你送人回来
Thanks for bringing him back
他们打坏的东西我会赔
I'll pay for the damages
不必了 ， 我自己还买得起
It's okay, I can afford them
仇老板 ， 小开在外边多少要点面子
Master Sua, Xiao Kai needs to retain his credibility
这件事他自己不会提 ， 仇老板？
he won't mention this incident, how about you?
光棍玲珑心 ， 余老板放心
Don't worry
好痛快 ， 不打不相识
if we hadn't fought, we wouldn't have met
仇老板 ， 以后要多多的照顾
Master Qiu, please take care
余老板太客气了
You are too kind
家里有些小兄弟只怕等得心急
My men are anxious for my return
我走了
I must go
不敢多留
Please
打电话叫曾老板来
Call Master Zeng
喂 ， 是的
Hello, yes
余公馆打来的
Call from the Yu Residence
喂
Hello
有这样的事
Really?
好 ， 我就来...
Alright, I'll come…
我看余震亭找我
I think Yu Zhen Ting wants me
一定是要我去对付仇连环
to deal with Qiu Lian Huan
那我们...
Then we…
余震亭太老了
He is too old
该回乡下去休息了
and should retire
不过他总是不肯自己走的
but he insists on staying
有办法 ， 小开是他的命根子
I have a plan, Xiao Kai is his life
告诉沉小姐 ， 仇老板来了
Tell Miss Shen, Master Qiu is here
是
Yes
我来了
I'm here
请坐
Please sit
余老板打过电话给我
Master Yu called me
我是你的了
I'm all yours
你好像并不欢迎我
You don't seem happy to see me
那有什么关系？
What has that to do with anything?
你喜欢我 ， 你已经抢到了我
You like me and have got me
那还不够吗？
isn't that enough?
你喜欢小开
You like Xiao Kai
小开？我只是可怜他
Xiao Kai? I merely pity him
小开能给你的我全能给你
I can give you whatever he could give you
说得对 ， 每一个男人都可以给我
Right, any man can give me that
别把我当成和别人一样
Don't take me for any man
有什么不同？
What's the difference?
你慢慢会知道的
You'll know in time
走
Let's go
老板 ， 到哪儿去？
Boss, where to?
回去
Go back
喂 ， 你会不会开车子？
Hey, do you know how to drive?
对不起 ， 一时控制不住 ， 真对不起
Sorry, I lost control
对不起就算啦
Sorry is not enough
算了 ， 看看车子还能不能开
Forget it. Let's see if the car can start
跟这种人吵什么
don't bother with this kind of people
是
Yes
上
Attack
仇老板 ， 乖乖地跟我们走
Master Qiu, please come with us
免得多吃苦头
and you'll not suffer
你们是谁的手下？
Who's your boss?
还有谁 ， 当然是余老板
It's Master Yu naturally
余震亭不会干这种不要脸的事
He wouldn't do such a lowly thing
你...
You…
让开
Sit aside
你怎么惹那么多麻烦？
Why have you got into so much trouble?
跟余震亭斗已经够了
To have to fight against Yu Zhen Ting is bad enough
又去惹曾根宝
and now you provoke Zeng Gen Bao too
他们是曾根宝的手下？
They are his men?
我们不是吃掉别人就是给人吃掉
We either destroy others or be destroyed
血？
Blood?
那是我的血
It's mine
走
Let's go
这个人要是不对付
If we don't deal with him
不知道要会做出什么事来
I don't know what he'll do
现在也够瞧的
He's ruthless enough
老大放心 ， 包在我身上
Don't worry, I'll take care of it
替小开出这口气
and avenge Xiao Kai
多谢大叔
Thank you, uncle
仇连环不是好对付的人
Qiu Lian Huan is no nice guy
老大 ， 小开还是少出去的好
Boss, it's best Xiao Kai went out less
我怕他啊 ， 偏要到处去
I'm not afraid of him, I'll deliberately go outside
一定要出去多带些人
Then take more men with you
我走了 ， 有什么事尽管找我好了
I'm going, contact me if you need anything
好
Alright
我是不是老了 ？
Am I getting old?
这样一个人都对付不了
I can't even deal with such a person
沉小姐 ， 我走了
Miss Shen, I'm going
别在我面前买狠劲
Don't play tough
你伤得很重
you're seriously wounded
出去要是再遇见曾根宝的人
If you bump into Zeng Gen Bao's men
你准没命
you'll be dead
你知道曾根宝是靠薄刀党起家的
You know he established himself by the Knife gang
手下多的是亡命之徒
they are desperados
我不要你可怜我
I don't want your pity
像你可怜小开一样
like you pity Xiao Kai
你别走
Don't go
在我这里养伤不会有人知道的
No one will know you are resting here
我不是可怜你 ， 是想帮你
I am not pitying you, I want to help you
为了一个女人被人打成这样值得吗
Is it worth it suffering for a woman?
不单是为了你
It's not only for you
我已经走了这条路
I've gone too far on this course
总会有这一天的
and will end up like this one day
我早就告诉过你们
I told you so
仇连环这个人不好对付
Qiu Lian Huan is no nice guy
怎么不打听清楚他带了多少人
Why don't you find out how many men he's brought?
他只带了三个人
He has only three men
我们有十几个人
We have over ten people
照说是可以把他弄回来的
we could get him back
弄回来？他人呢
Get him back? Where is he?
我想他也一定受了伤
He must be wounded
就算他躲起来
Even if he's gone into hiding
向他手下逼问
we could get his whereabouts from his men
也一定可以追问出来的
with a bit of force
那还不快去
Then do it now
是...走
Yes…let's go
余小开的事情迟几天再说
We'll deal with Yu Xiao Kai's matter later
是...
Yes…
走
Let's go
上
Go
别动
Don't move
仇老板在不在？
Is Master Qiu here?
他不在 ， 你们是...
No, you're…
什么事？
What's the matter?
林更生 ， 有人要找你说话
Lin Geng Sheng, someone's looking for you
什么人？
Who?
曾根宝曾老板
Master Zeng Gen Bao
我算什么角色
Who am I
曾老板是大亨
to have such an honourl
找我有什么话说？
What does he want me for?
你去不去？
Are you going or not?
怕什么？
What's to fear?
光棍命一条又不是租来的
My life is cheap
死了不拖不欠
it matters not even if I die
好爽快
So resolute
放心 ， 我们曾老板不会亏待你的
Don't worry, Master Zeng will treat you well
进去找一找
Let's go and look inside
要是仇老板在 ， 一起请去
If Master Qiu is in please invite him to come along
是
Yes
仇老板不在
Master Qiu is not here
他出了什么事？
What has happened to him?
不大不小
Not that serious
打死了曾老板手下十几个小兄弟
He killed Master Zeng's men
他出去就没有回来过
He has not returned since going out
我也不知道他在什么地方
I don't know where he has gone
对曾老板说去
Tell Master Zeng by yourself
我不知道他在什么地方
I don't know where he has gone
他要是受了伤会到什么地方养伤
If he's injured where would he seek help?
我不知道
I don't know
想不到仇连环硬
Qiu Lian Huan is tough
他手下也硬
I little expect his man to be tough too
告诉你我要找他
I tell you I want to find him
不管他躲在什么地方
regardless of where he's hiding
我一定能把他找出来
I'll find him
那你自己去找好了
Then look for him yourself
到我自己把他找出来的时候
When I find him
林更生 ， 你也没有好日子过了
you will have trouble
仇老板手下不算你
Apart from you, Master Qiu
还有五十四个弟兄 ， 是不是啊？
has 54 men, right?
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
我花了四十八根大条子
I've bought 48 of them
有六个不肯收
but 6 refused
都解决了
They have all been eliminated
你这样辣手
You are cruel
林更生 ， 你当然不止值一根大条子
Lin Geng Sheng, you're of course worth more
十根怎么样？
How about ten?
怎么样？
Well?
仇老板跟我的交情不买
My relation with Master Qiu is not for sale
好 ， 那你走吧
Alright, go then
你们好好送他出去
See him out properly
送到这里够了 ， 请回吧
It's okay, please return
要送你到西天
We want to see that you die
告诉曾根宝
Tell Zeng Gen Bao
我林更生今天虽然死了
even if I die today
把这些塞进他肚子里用麻袋装好
Stuff these into his stomach and put him in a bag
走
Let's go
我要打个电话给林更生好让他放心
I must call Lin Geng Sheng so he'll not worry
明天再打吧
Do it tomorrow
喂 ， 是 ， 仇老板
Hello, yes, Master Qiu
没事 ， 找林更生
Nothing much, looking for Lin Geng Sheng
您找林更生啊？
Looking for Lin Geng Sheng?
仇老板 ， 你在哪里？
Master Qiu, where are you?
你是谁？
Who are you?
他...仇老板 ， 我是阿毛
Master Qiu, I am Ah Mo
你有什么事对我说好了
just tell me what you want
你在什么地方？
Where are you?
好 ， 找林更生来听电话
Right, get Lin Geng Sheng on the phone
他出去了
He has gone out
你的电话多少？他回来...
What's your number? When he comes back…
不行 ， 我要回去看看
No, I must go back
一定有毛病
something must be wrong
要是有毛病你更不能出去了
In that case you should all the more not go out
我替你去打听去
I'll investigate for you
也好 ， 不过你不能说我在你这里
Alright, but you can't say I am here
我又不是傻子
I am no fool
我把仇连环的手下全买过来了
I've bought Qiu Lian Huan's all men
又把林更生肚子里头塞了铅块
I've also filled Lin Geng Sheng's stomach with lead
扔进了黄浦江
and threw him into the Wang Pao river
仇连环吓得一定跑到了乡下
Qiu Lian Huan must have fled to the village for fear
再也不敢到上海来了
and dare not come to Shanghai
我看这不像仇连环做的事
Doesn't seem like how Qiu Lian Huan would handle things
小开 ， 沉菊芳又是你的了
Xiao Kai, Shen Ju Fang is yours again
老大年纪大了 ， 顾忌太多
The boss is getting old, he's much too concerned
大叔 ， 你说得对
Uncle, you're right
今天又赢了
I've won again today
好香啊
Smells good
好甜里
So sweet
讨厌
Naughty
今天好像少了一个人
It looks like we miss one person today
仇连环 ， 他完了
Qiu Lian Huan is finished
还提他干什么
Don't mention him again
他手下全部让曾老板给买去了
His men have been bought by Master Zeng
那他得力的帮手林更生呢？
What about his assistant Lin Geng Sheng?
肚子里装了铅
His stomach has been filled with lead
给海龙王召去做女婿了
and he has been drowned
喂
Hello
小开真有一手
Xiao Kai is really good
余先生 ， 电话
Sir, your telephone
喂 ， 好
Hello, alright
等我来 ， 先别打他
Wait till I've arrived, don't beat him up yet
等我来 ， 让我给他吃生活
When I get there I'll give him a painful time
抓到仇连环了
We've found Qiu Lian Huan
我先让他吃一顿生活
Let me give him a hard time first
抓到仇连环了 ？在哪儿抓到的
Where did you find him?
在浦东乡下抓回来的
In the village of Pui Tung
晚上在家里等我
Wait for me at home tonight
来了 ， 快点
Coming, hurry
不要跑 ， 站住
Stop running, stand still
打架滚远一点
If you want to fight, go elsewhere
我们是仇老板的兄弟 ， 听见了没有
We're Master Qiu's brothers, hear that?
听见了
Yes
快...
Quickly…
你在 ， 你还在
You're still here
怎么了 ？
What's the matter?
小开接到电话说是抓到了你
Xiao Kai received a call saying that you've been caught
开玩笑
It must be ajoke
我看不像是开玩笑
I don't think so
那电话是熟人打给他的
It was a call from a friend
他听了立刻就走了
He left right away after he hung up
别管他
Never mind him
你打听的事情怎么样？
What news have you got?
到底怎么样？
What about it?
你完了
You're finished
我怎么会完？
How can I?
曾根宝把你手下全买了过去
Zeng Gen Bao has bought off all your men
每人一根大条子
Each one has been well paid
林更生呢？他不会出卖我
What about Lin Geng Sheng? He won't betray me
林更生给他们肚子里塞了铅
They threw Lin Geng Sheng
扔进黄浦江去
down into the river
现在你就一个人 ， 伤又没有好
You're all by yourself now, you haven't recuperated yet
会白送了性命的
You'll kill yourself
是 ， 我该躲着
Yes, I'd better go on hiding
躲在一个女人家里做缩头乌龟
Hide at a woman's home and be a coward
不敢出去见人
and dare not see people
仇连环 ， 你说话清楚点儿
Qiu Lian Huan, watch your mouth
我是你的人 ， 这是你的地方
I'm at your mercy, and this is your place
等你伤好了随便你怎么样
You can do whatever you want after you've recuperated
现在你给我坐下
Now, sit down
我没有空
I've no time
我还有许多朋友
I still have a lot of friends
我会去找他们
I'll go and find them
我有很多朋友
I have a lot of friends
别太相信你那些流氓朋友
Don't trust those scumbags
他们是我朋友 ， 跟我一样
They are my friends, they are like me
也跟曾根宝一样
They are like Zeng Gen Bao too
闭嘴
Shut up
我要是怕你 ， 我也不跟你
If I was afraid of you, I wouldn't have been with you
号外...快来看号外
Extra…Come for the Extra…
给我来一份 ， 给我一份
Give me one
"Son of Yu Zhen Ting is kidnapped"
对方有消息没有？
Any news?
有
Yes
要多少钱？
How much they want?
不要钱
Nothing
要我离开上海
Want me to leave Shanghai
我早就该离开上海
I should have left earlier
像我这种人会有什么好结果
There won't be a happy ending for a person like me
这里的事情
I have already handed over
我本来已经有一半交给你
half of the business here to you
另一半你派人去接
Send someone to handle the other half
我明天就走
I'll leave tomorrow
老大 ， 别难过了
Brother, don't be upset
等小开一回来咱们再打主意
We'll think of something when Xiao Kai comes back
算了
Never mind
根宝 ， 你从搞薄刀党起
Gen Bao, you've been with me
也算跟我出身
ever since the Knife gang first started
我只有他一个儿子
He's my only son
你不能太狠心
Don't be too harsh on him
老大 ， 你这什么意思？
Boss, what do you mean?
算了 ， 根宝
Gen Bao, never mind
仇连环不会提这样条件的
Qiu Lian Huan wouldn't put up such conditions
在俱乐部
At the club
他是接到熟人的电话才走的
he left after he received a call from friends
我虽然老还不糊涂啊
Although I am old, I am not stupid
老大要是疑心我
If you suspect me
我跟你一块走好了
I'll go with you
不必了
No need
根宝 ， 好好提防
Gen Bao, be careful
小心一报还一报
You'll be treated the same way you treat others
明天我走了
When I leave tomorrow
你们跟我还是不跟？
will you go with me?
我们跟曾老板
We'll stay with Master Zeng
好 ， 好
Alright
曾老板有一件差事要我们办
Master Zeng has an errand for us
余老板别怪啊
Master Yu, please don't blame us
叫根宝进来见我
Ask Gen Bao to come to me
曾老板带人去几家公司点货去了
Master Zeng went to examine goods at some companies
你...你们
You…
小开被人抓去了
Xiao Kai has been caught
抓小开的自称是你的手下
The one who caught Xiao Kai claimed to be your man
我到俱乐部去走了走
I've been to the club
那里的人说余震亭死了
and they said that Yu Zhen Ting is dead
曾根宝出面替他治丧
Zeng Gen Bao is taking care of his funeral
又说曾根宝已经派人接下了
They also said that Zeng Gen Bao
余震亭全部的地盘
has taken over all of Yu Zhen Ting's business
我看小开也遭了毒手
I'm afraid Xiao Kai might have been killed too
事情现在很明白了
The matter is now very clear
全是曾根宝一个人在捣鬼
It's Zeng Gen Bao who is playing all the tricks
现在他的势力比余震亭早年更大
He is now more powerful than Yu Zhen Ting used to be
不管他势力多大 ， 我一样要找他
No matter how powerful he is, I've to find him
等你伤好了再说
Better wait until you recuperate
菊芳 ， 昨天晚上我能叫你求饶
Ju Fang, I made you so happy last night
你还说我的伤没有好
how can you say that I haven't recuperated
今晚我得去找人
Tonight I must go and find some help
再过两天他根基一稳
otherwise he'll grow in power
更难对付了
and make it more difficult to deal with him
你祸闯得不小啊
You've got into big troubles
快去避避风头
you'd better go on hiding
少盘费的话我这里有
If you are in need of money, I can give it to you
刚才我说的...
What I've mentioned just now…
不要嫌少
It's not much, please don't mind
这里是...
This is…
老兄要知道 ， 曾根宝在找你
Zeng Gen Bao is looking for you
我这里不便久留
You can't stay here for long
干什么？
What's wrong?
我和你们老板是换帖的兄弟
Your boss and I are sworn brothers
"Sworn brothers"
放心 ， 你的事就是我的事
Don't worry, your troubles are mine too
在我这里我的人随便你用
Make yourself at home
我还当朋友全不要我
Those who I called friends all deserted me
哪有这回事
It isn't like that
我还要走几家 ， 再和你联络
I still need to go somewhere else, we'll be in touch
你别走
Don't go
为什么？
Why?
老兄弟 ， 你来了总该叙叙
Brother, since you are here we should have a chat
好 ， 好 ， 这就是好朋友
Alright, this is what good friends are for
曾根宝来了代我问候他
When Zeng Gen Bao comes, give him my regards
更生
Geng Sheng
你和我走的路上没有一个是人
None of those who are with us are human enough
我和你也全不是人
Neither of us are
"Qing Lin Tower"
买报...先生买报
Newspapers…Come for a newspaper
买报
Newspapers…
仇老板 ， 你真有种啊
Master Qiu, you have guts
你才有种
You too
余震亭把你拉起来
Yu Zhen Ting has helped you before
你用这样的手段对付他
how can you treat him like this?
你不吃人 ， 人就吃你
It's a world where the fittest survive
你说得对
You are right
仇连环 ， 你肯伏地求饶包你没事
Qiu Lian Huan, beg for pardon and you'll be alright
我不会
I definitely won't
这条路我也不想再走下去了
I am tired of this life
对不起 ， 请两位避一避
Sorry, please leave now
走...
Go…
动家伙
Grab the weapons
曾老板算看得起我姓仇的
Master Zeng looks highly on me after all
把你的老本钱薄刀党都派出来了
You've even sent your favourite Knife gang
仇连环 ， 你现在只有两条路
Qiu Lian Huan, you have two options
一条是伏低跟我
One is to serve me
除了我曾某人
If you do
你就坐第二把交椅
you'll be my right hand
还有一条嘛 ， 就是死
If not, you'll die
跟你这种人还不如死
I'd rather die than to serve you
不过我姓仇的今天就算死在这里
But even if I have to die
也会先给林更生报仇
I'll avenge for Lin Geng Sheng first
"Hui Le Lane"
仇连环刚才中了一刀
Qiu Lian Huan has just been stabbed
连肠子都看见了 ， 别怕他
His stomach is cut open, don't be afraid of him
杀了他
Kill him
仇连环已经不行了
Qiu Lian Huan is finished
上
Attack
走...快
Go…hurry
"Qiu Lian Huan was killed"